Excuse me, sir. Sir!
Question for you, real quick.
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
Uh, 18.
Yes, sir.
And how did you get rich?
I dropped out of college and pursued my dream.
What's your dream?
I became an NBA player.
An NBA player?
Yes.
For what team?
For the Boston Celtics.
Are you Jalen Brown?
I am.
Excuse me, sir. Sir!
Question for you.
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
I know who you are, bro.
Yeah.
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
How did you get rich?
I'm an inventor.
You're an inventor?
Yeah.
What did you invent?
I created your favorite beer.
What beer?
Samuel Adams.
You created Samuel Adams?
40 years ago in my kitchen.
What was the most amount of
money you made in a single year?
I made 50 million last year.
Well, the company was last valued at 3.6 billion.
That was like 2 billion dollars.
If your ambition is to
become a billionaire, good f***ing luck.
Guys, I just landed in one of
the richest cities in the entire world.
For the first time ever, I'm in Boston, Massachusetts.
Home to over 40,000 millionaires and over 10 billionaires.
And today, I'm going to be going around the richest
areas in Boston to find these billionaires,
the richest people in Boston, to figure out
what they did to build their
wealth, become billionaires, become financially free, and
how you can follow their exact secrets and
blueprint to become a wealthy in today's world.
So this video is about to
be insane from start to finish.
So stay tuned until the end.
With that being said, let's
get this video on the way.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir.
Question for you.
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
In my 20s.
In your 20s?
And how did you get rich?
I'm an inventor.
You're an inventor?
Yeah.
What did you invent?
Have you ever seen one of these?
The Whoop?
You created Whoop?
Yeah.
Where did you build the company?
I started in 2012, so I've been
building the business for the last 12 years.
And how old are you today?
Over these 12 years, what was the most
amount of money you made in a single year?
Well, the company was last valued at 3.6 billion,
so at this point, we've had some pretty big years.
So you own a billion-dollar company.
Yeah.
It's been an amazing journey.
I go all over the world
interviewing billionaires to help the younger generation.
Can I get in the middle
with you for our channel real quick?
Let's do it.
Did you go to college?
Yeah, I went to Harvard.
You went to Harvard.
So you knew when you were at Harvard that
you were not going to go work for anybody else?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Now, you could argue working for yourself
is more work than working for someone else.
Was entrepreneurship innate in you?
I think at the end of the day, I
was driven by the problem I was trying to solve.
It wasn't like I said
I wanted to start a company.
What company should I start?
It was like, I want to start this company.
I want to understand health.
I want to be able to build
wearable devices that millions of people understand.
Yeah.
And then use to improve their health.
That was always the vision.
I'm going to challenge you right here.
Give me a lesson about business that
is not taught in business school at Harvard.
I'll say this.
A lot is said of CEOs needing to
have vision and empathy and strategy and business acumen.
The single trait that I've found is the
hardest trait in all of building business is courage.
Your courage is going to be tested before
anything else when you're in a real problem.
Can you say the hard thing?
Can you do the hard thing?
Can you walk into the problem and own it?
Nobody talks about courage.
And they don't teach you that in business
school and you can't read it in a book.
And so that's, I think, the single hardest thing to being a CEO
is when shit really goes wrong, you're going to need to have courage.
That's something you have to develop over time.
When was your courage tested?
Oh, look.
I mean, there were various points in the company's history where we almost
ran out of money, where we almost missed payroll, where the product was failing.
Did you almost go broke?
Yeah, of course.
The company almost failed.
I was a broke entrepreneur, you know,
six or seven years into building it.
So seven years in, you could have gave everything up.
But you didn't.
Why not?
What kept you going?
Well, this is a crazy story.
I remember in 2015, I was
sitting on my couch, my parents' home.
Whoop was kind of still struggling to go along.
And I'm watching NBA basketball.
And what comes on the screen but a Kia commercial.
And in the Kia commercial,
LeBron James is wearing a Whoop.
And what was amazing about that is at the time,
there was only 100 Whoop straps in the entire world.
Your watch?
Yeah.
And one of them was on arguably the
greatest athlete in the world at the time.
And so when you're a fledgling entrepreneur and you're busy.
And you're broke.
And you're trying to figure out how to make it.
Having these little moments of inspiration where you're
like, wow, maybe this does have a chance.
If he's wearing it, maybe
a lot of other people will.
Like, it gives you a second wind.
Do you think everybody's built for entrepreneurship?
No.
I mean, entrepreneurship is a lesson in
pain and suffering for a greater cause.
And that's just something that some people
want to wake up every day and do.
And it's something that, you know, isn't for everyone.
Yeah, I remember Elon Musk said one time that
entrepreneurship is like eating glass and staring into the abyss.
And look, he's done it for, you know, 30 years.
He hasn't built iconic businesses.
How do you feel about competition?
Were you ever afraid to go into a competitive market?
No.
I mean, in some ways, we
don't pay much attention to competition.
And in other ways, we just want to kill competition.
So that's the balance you always want to have.
So talking about killing the competition, the one
thing that you're doing differently from everybody else.
Well, we've built a product that's fully
integrated, that has a brand associated with it,
that really has the best data associated with it.
And that sort of collection of unique elements has
made it a product that people love and wear.
And we've seen companies like
Amazon, for example, knock this off.
and I tried to create an exact copycat product.
And they had all the distribution, but the product failed
because it was missing some of that magic.
Amazon tried to copy you.
Yeah, totally tried to copy us.
Really?
Yeah.
But you don't care that
they're a titan in their space
and that they're the size of
the company that they are today.
You don't care about that.
Well, we certainly took it seriously
when they came out with the product,
but we also said, we're going to win.
In fact, we wrote on every circuit board,
don't bother copying us, we will win.
My last question for you, in 30 seconds,
give us the blueprint to building a billion-dollar company.
Honestly, I think you've got to find something you love
and be obsessed with it and chase
it and chase it and chase it.
No one is entitled to be a great entrepreneur.
No one's entitled to build a great business.
And so you put that entitlement aside
and you go do the hard work
that other people aren't doing,
and you look at a problem a little bit differently,
and then it's persistence, persistence, persistence.
You find a great team, you raise capital,
and then boom, you'll do something special.
And just like that, we're
going to build a billion-dollar business.
Exactly.
You've got amazing advice, my friend.
Thank you so much for your time.
This was a pleasure. Thank you, man.
You guys, he built a multi-billion-dollar company.
He said his company was valuable.
At over $3.5 billion.
And he's the founder of Whoop, one of the fastest-growing,
one of the biggest healthcare
technology companies in the entire world.
And that entire interview was a straight masterclass.
It's safe to say I
don't think that advice is given
to any Harvard Business School class whatsoever,
but only here at the School of Hard Knocks.
But we've got to keep this one rolling
and go get another interview out here, you guys.
Come on.
All right, you guys, I have
a very special surprise for you all.
I'm at MIT right now,
one of the most prestigious schools in the entire world.
And I'm about to interview Jalen Brown,
the NBA ambassador,
Boston Celtics legend.
You want to know something crazy about him?
He's the sixth highest-paid player in the entire NBA.
He's one of the richest athletes in the world.
He made over $49 million this last year.
So I'm going to be
linking up with him at MIT
to figure out what he did
to become one of the highest-paid players in the NBA,
what led to his success,
and what he's doing to preserve that kind of money.
So this one's about to be crazy,
but let's go link up with Jalen right now
and go see what he has to say.
How you doing, man?
Great to meet you.
You too.
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
How old was I?
Yeah.
Yes, sir.
And how did you get rich?
I dropped out of college and pursued my dream.
What's your dream?
I became an NBA player.
An NBA player?
Yes.
For what team?
For the Boston Celtics.
Are you Jalen Brown?
I am.
You became one of the greatest athletes alive.
What was the biggest driving factor of your success
that enabled you to work your way up
and become a professional basketball player
at the highest of the industry?
Adversity and failure.
Yeah, I think people think there's a negative perception
to adversity and failure.
I actually, like, seek it.
The more I fail, those have
been the blessings in my life.
The more I've had adversity,
it unlocks work ethic, it unlocks discipline,
and it unlocks creativity.
So, I fail more.
What was the most amount of money
that you made in a single year?
I guess last season.
How much?
I made $50 million last year.
$50 million?
Yeah.
Do you keep a lot of money in the bank?
No, and the richest people never do.
Why not?
Because they understand that money is just paper.
I think that what people value the most is subjective,
but a lot of the richest people,
social capital is what they're after.
Are you a good negotiator?
I'm a great negotiator.
So, you're not afraid to walk away from a deal
if it doesn't align with you?
I will run away from it.
I'm okay.
I'm not very materialistic.
I'm grateful.
You're also not desperate.
I'm not.
You know what I mean?
I have more than enough than I've ever had.
So, I'm extremely grateful.
I do a lot of philanthropy work.
You don't come for money?
No.
Single parent household, apartment,
bunk bed with my brother.
We had necessities,
but at times we went without things,
water, light, et cetera.
So, it's amazing to be
able to provide for my mom,
my family, my intermediate family, in a sense, too.
So, I'm very blessed.
Now, the most successful people in the world,
they inevitably deal with a lot of hate.
How do you feel about haters?
About haters?
It's a part of it, you know?
When you have haters,
that means you're doing something right.
I mean, I think that just comes with it.
I don't let it, like, discourage me.
I don't let it stop me.
They don't build statues for haters.
They build statues for people that do things.
You know what I mean?
How old are you now?
I'm 28.
If me and you died tomorrow
and you had one more guiding principle
to lead with the younger generation,
what would that be?
The moon steals light from the sun,
but people never get the two confused.
What does that mean?
We were just talking about, like, haters and imitators.
People will imitate you,
take your style,
imitate your brand,
or, you know, take your lingo,
everything that you do.
But the moon may steal light from the sun,
but the sun is still the sun.
It still shines every day.
We won't get the two confused.
Did you ever doubt yourself?
I have, many a times.
I've dealt with anxiety, even depression.
I've been to some very dark places,
to be honest, mentally.
But I feel like those dark places
have allowed my light to shine.
How did you overcome that?
Talk to somebody at rock bottom right now.
I would say it's okay.
It's all right.
I know what you're feeling and experience.
I know that feeling of what you're going through,
the doubt, the fear,
the lack of trust that you may have in yourself.
But just remind yourself
that you can do great things,
that you can and you will.
Everybody's gonna deal with adversity at some point,
and they're like every living being,
every living organism,
even plants struggle to get sunlight.
Do you believe in God?
I do.
And anytime I've ever been alone,
I've just always filled that space with the most high,
and he's always guided me.
Faith, consistency, and hard work pays off.
You got amazing advice, my friend.
Thank you so much for your time.
No problem.
I appreciate that, man.
That was awesome.
Yes, sir. Appreciate you.
Guys, a billionaire that I interviewed once told me this.
Every opportunity that I've ever had
started with an email.
And that hit me,
because most of us are not born great writers,
and I know I wasn't.
But when you're building a business,
writing is how you pitch,
lead,
hire,
and connect with other people.
And trust me when I tell you this,
if your message isn't clear,
it will be ignored.
And that's why I use Grammarly Pro,
because it helps me write clearly,
it sounds exactly like myself,
and I move way faster.
Now, Grammarly's great,
because it has a free version
that handles grammar,
tone,
and clarity.
But Grammarly Pro is where it really gets powerful,
because I can literally rewrite my paragraphs
that I'm writing in just one click.
I can set writing goals,
so my writing fits exactly who I'm talking to,
whether I'm trying to be formal,
friendly,
or even persuasive.
And the sidebar feature
lets me fine-tune
the tone,
impact,
and flow in real time.
So guys,
I cannot stress this enough.
When your words are doing
the heavy lifting of business,
every sentence matters.
And that's exactly why I use Grammarly.
So to start now for free,
go down and click the link
in the description of this video,
or go to grammarly.com
slash hardknock08
and use my link for 20% off Grammarly Pro.
But with that being said,
let's get back to the video.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir, question for you.
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
I know who you are, bro.
Yeah.
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
30 years old?
Yeah.
And what line of business are you in?
How did you get rich?
Finance.
And now I'm a CEO of a company.
What were you doing in finance?
I worked at a hedge fund for 21 years,
one of the senior partners there.
Had, you know, great success.
That allowed me to be a philanthropist
and trying to do some good in the world.
So you ran a hedge fund?
I was one of the managing partners, yeah.
How much money were you guys managing?
Almost $40 billion.
You guys were managing $40 billion?
Yeah.
Did you come from a lot of money?
No.
I grew up poor.
I was in the projects,
Englewood, California.
I lived in a trailer in rural North Carolina.
And I got a series
of people to invest in me
and give me the opportunity to prove myself.
I work my ass off.
And then got just a series of breaks
that I took advantage of.
What's a lesson that you learned on the street
that translated into the business world?
Learn how to dribble with your left.
Don't rely on what comes natural,
what comes easy.
Like, constantly look for those other things
to supplement the things that you already have.
Where do the richest people in the world
put their money?
I think the smartest people
know what they know
and know what they don't know.
Put it in an index fund.
Give me some game right here.
Vanguard.
Put your money in an index fund.
Cheap way, reliable way.
What specific index fund?
S&P 500.
Like, don't be overly complicated.
Like, too often,
we invest in this small idea
and that small idea
compound wealth over time.
What was the most amount of money
that you made in a single year?
More importantly than how much
I made in a single year
is how much I gave away
to help others.
Judge me by that.
Like, a lot of people
think about, you know,
cars and rings.
When you're lying on your deathbed,
the last thing that you're thinking about
is the next thing that you bought
or the next thing that you want to buy.
I think it's the amount of people
that you help,
the amount of people in your life
that you love
more important than anything else.
How much did you give away in a year?
I've given away more than most.
No, I just think that
judging yourself,
on that basis,
rather than how many chips you stack,
is, for me,
a much more thoughtful way to live life.
Do you think money buys happiness?
It does not.
Money just makes you more
of what you already are.
Do you believe in God?
Oh, I believe in God.
I mean, God has ordered my steps,
guided my path.
The only way that I went
from where I was to where I am
is by the grace of God.
Faith has been important for you.
Faith has been key for me, yes.
I know you're a man of faith.
I am.
It's the only thing that matters
at the end of the day.
It really is.
Because the money's temporary.
It's a dying dead road.
There are plenty of rich people
with no days left,
and what good is that?
What's the best financial decision
you made throughout your career?
Marrying an extraordinary person.
Because, you know,
when you're partnered
with someone who's extraordinary,
who loves you,
they have your back,
you're going to grow
everything together.
Everything that you do
is going to be touched
and blessed by God.
Everything that you work on,
you're going to be working on
not just by yourself,
but with someone else
who's equally motivated
for you to be successful.
That's the single best decision
that you can make,
is marrying someone great.
How long have you been married?
27 years.
How long have you been faithful?
That was a really easy question
and a really easy answer.
You never doubted it one bit?
You never questioned it?
No, because when you make
a decision like that
that's blessed by God,
you don't destroy it.
Your best dating advice
to a young entrepreneur,
somebody that's focused
on wanting to make it
in today's world,
how did you know
you found your way?
What's the single
most important characteristic
that you look for
in a life partner?
Focus on the character.
So many people
pick a spouse
based on the exterior only.
Focus on what's inside.
Focus on the character.
How old are you now?
I'm 51.
What's your name?
Daman.
If me and you died tomorrow
and you had one more
guiding principle
to the younger generation,
what would that be?
Self-interest is essential
but selfishness is not.
People need help right now
so do something
to help somebody today.
You got amazing advice, sir.
I appreciate it.
Thank you so much
for your time.
I appreciate it.
You guys,
we just interviewed somebody
that worked at and ran
one of the biggest hedge funds
in the entire country
and just gave us
a beautiful interview.
He said the best financial
decision was what?
Once again,
it points back to
the woman that you decide
to marry.
It's either going to be
your greatest asset
or your greatest liability.
Another great interview
out here in Boston.
We got to keep this one rolling
and go see who else
we can find out here,
you guys.
Come on.
Guys,
I got another special
surprise for you all right now.
I'm about to go interview
a billionaire
who built his wealth
from selling beer.
He's the creator
of Samuel Adams
and the Boston Beer Company.
He's the beer mogul.
I've never interviewed
a billionaire
that got rich this way.
This is going to be
unlike any interview
I've ever done
but let's go meet up
with him right now
and go see what he has to say.
Awesome.
Here, here.
This is James.
James.
Nice to meet you, sir.
Pleasure to meet you.
Thank you for having us out.
We really appreciate that.
Thank you for coming here.
Yeah, this is super fun.
It's kind of out of the way place
in Boston.
We're like at the end
of civilization
so I'm glad you found us.
Well, you made it worth it
for us to be out here
so we appreciate that.
And of course,
we do have a bar.
Yeah.
After the interview,
if you don't mind,
I'll have to have one drink up here.
All right.
How did you get rich?
I created your favorite beer.
What beer?
Samuel Adams.
You created Samuel Adams?
Yes, I did.
40 years ago in my kitchen.
What was the most amount
of money you made
in a single year?
That was like $2 billion.
What did you learn
about branding?
Because obviously
the Samuel Adams,
it's iconic.
It's in all the airports.
It's in all the concerts.
What have you learned
about branding
that enables you
to get into all
the distribution
that's possible?
I learned branding's
not that important.
You know,
when I was trying
to figure out a name for it,
I had lists of names.
I boiled it down
to like two names
and they were
about equally popular
with people
that I would ask about them
and I looked back on it
and I called it Sam Adams.
I could have called it
New World Boston Lager.
I think it would have been
just as successful
because at the end of the day,
marketing is very overrated.
Really?
What really works
is a better product.
I mean, ask yourself,
how much stuff do you buy
because of fancy marketing
versus products
that are actually superior?
That's what people want
and we had
a better glass of beer.
So you think people,
they put too much emphasis
on marketing
and they should be focused
on building a winning product.
And working your ass off
to sell it.
That was what worked
for Sam Adams.
Six weeks after
we hit the market,
we got picked
as the best beer in America.
The company was two people.
Here we are.
We are making
the best beer in America.
We didn't hire
our first marketing person
for 10 years.
But by the time
we hired one marketing person,
we had 80 sales people.
Selling is underrated.
Marketing is overrated.
Now take me back
to the most life-changing
conversation that you ever had.
You know, it actually came
from my uncle.
And he was a really
very smart guy.
Worked really hard.
Worked his way up
at Goldman Sachs
without an MBA or anything.
He was in sales.
And I remember he called me
and he was one of my
original investors.
And he asked me,
well, what did you do today, Jim?
And I said,
well, I went and shopped
for computers.
I went up to New Hampshire
where there's no sales tax
because I needed
to save that money.
And I looked at a computer.
I hadn't bought anything yet.
And he cut me off.
He says, oh, computers.
You know, Jim,
I've seen a lot of businesses
that went broke.
And they all had computers.
But they went broke
because they didn't
have any sales.
Go out and start selling your beer.
Do you have any customers yet?
And I said, well,
not yet.
You know, I was trying
to get everything set up.
And frankly,
I was just scared shitless
to go out and cold call on bars
because I never sold
anything in my life.
He said, go out
and get one customer every day
and don't come home
until you got that customer.
So you can't be afraid
to go sell your product?
No, you're the best
salesperson there is
if you genuinely believe
in your product.
That authenticity
is very powerful.
Being a slick salesman
is way overrated.
Being genuine, sincere, authentic,
that's a big deal.
People don't see that so often.
They say that sales
cures everything.
That's exactly right.
You know, no business went broke
because they had too many sales.
How did you get the money
to start and grow this business?
I stripped everything down.
What do I really need?
Not what I want,
not what I'd like to have.
What is the absolute minimum
I need to start this business?
And how do I start a business
on a shoestring?
So, for example,
I found a way
that I didn't have
to build a brewery.
I found an existing brewery
where I could contract
my production.
I realized,
I don't need an office
because I can use bars
to do business.
I can have business meetings there.
So, I didn't have an office
for a year.
I did everything
from pay phone booths.
I could tell you
where all the good
pay phone booths were
in Boston.
And I focused on
absolute minimum of things.
I needed to buy
great ingredients,
so I brought in hops
from Bavaria.
I needed the best brewmaster
in the world to help me,
so I went out and hired him.
He was the guy
who invented
light beer.
And I couldn't really
afford what he cost,
but I gave him
2% of the company,
which turned out
pretty well for him.
So, I just skinnied
everything down.
What's the absolute
minimum I need?
And threw off
what I don't need.
You invested all your money
back into the business?
For the first, like,
15 years.
Absolutely.
At what point
did you diversify?
Well, we went public
in 1995.
You guys are public.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And this is another
good piece of advice.
If you get to the point
where you can go public,
keep the voting room.
We have all the voting shares.
So, we went public,
but I have
all the voting shares.
You don't want anybody
else to control your baby.
Exactly.
And do you think
that's the risk
of taking on
too much investors?
Is that,
and you give away control
and say away to others?
Yeah, yeah.
I basically sacrifice
some of the economics
for control,
because I don't want
to work my ass off
every day for somebody else.
You started this thing,
you're going to make
the decisions.
Yeah, I'm a really,
really terrible employee.
I love that.
And you learned
that early on in the city?
In my entire life,
I've never had a boss.
How old are you now?
And what's your name?
Jim Cook.
Jim, if me and you
died tomorrow,
and you could leave
one more God and principle
with the younger generation
to build the business
of their dreams,
what would that be?
If your ambition
is to become a billionaire,
good fucking luck.
But if your ambition
is something different,
like I want to make
great beer,
I want to create
a beer revolution
in the United States,
which is why I named
my beer after
the great revolutionary
Sam Adams.
If you have those
kind of meaningful ambitions,
you'll do well.
And in some ways,
getting rich
is life's
biggest booby prize.
People who aren't happy
want to get rich.
You know,
what would you rather be?
Rich or happy?
Happy.
There you go.
You got amazing advice, sir.
Thank you so much
for your time.
I appreciate that.
My pleasure.
Guys, we just interviewed
the billionaire founder
of Samuel Adams.
He became a billionaire
from selling beer.
But I need you guys
to like and subscribe
for amazing content
I've got coming every week
because I'm literally
traveling the world
going to find and interview
the richest people
in every city
around the world.
And guys,
I'm going to take things
a step further.
See, I give you
direct access
to the people I interview,
the multimillionaires
and billionaires
I interview every single week
inside of my private
entrepreneur community
that I've built
to become the number one
online community
for business owners
in the world
where you can join,
get direct access
to the people
that I'm interviewing
on live calls every week
and ask your specific questions
to the people
that I'm interviewing.
What do you think
would happen to you
in your life,
the trajectory of your business
if you had the ability
to get mentored
every single week
by the millionaires
and billionaires
that I interview?
Well, I'm giving you
direct access right now.
All you have to do
is go down
and click the link
in the description
of this video
to join the number one
community for business owners
in the entire world.
I can't wait to see you
on the inside.
That being said,
I'll see you in the next video.